BERTON YUDHO SIMANULLANG

+6281210190581



berton.simanulang@gmail.com



Bojonggede, Bogor 16320



SUMMARY

has a hobby and interest in the infra field since starting career as a support technician in early 2015 at an iot product startup, has been interested in the cloud since 2017 as a server administrator, namely Amazon Web Services, further exploring AWS products, and infra tools such as Nginx, Container, Virtualization and even GCP until now.

EDUCATION

Support Engineer

Binus University

Information Systems 2022 – present

SKILLS

- Containerization
- Virtualization
- · Apache, Nginx
- MySQL
- Amazon Web Services
- Google Cloud Platform
- Microsoft Azure
- Git
- Mikrotik
- ISO 27001
- Ansible
- Terraform

TRAINING & CERTIFICATION

• May, 2024 AWS Academy Graduate - AWS Cloud Developing https://www.credly.com/go/8PrwxoCZ

• January, 2024 ISO 27001 Certification

• January, 2015 Graduate Professional Program - CCIT FT UI

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Support Engineer

Kita Indonesia Plus | 2022 - Present

- responsible for IT Infrastructure and Office Operations
- managing Cloud Environment
- · managing on prime Environment
- setup monitoring tools
- manage and monitoring Container applications
- administrate mail server using Google Workspace
- troubleshooting, logging Server environment

Tech Support Officer

MNC Digital Indonesia | 2019 - 2022

- Responsible for Livestream Infrastructure preparation, such as Hardware, Network, RTMP, Clouds, etc
- Responsible for back office user troubleshooting
- . Responsible in IT asset Management
- Handling IT Documentation

Tech Support & Server Administrator

Jukir co | 2017 - 2019

- Assisting field team in solving application issue
- Setup environment
- Monitoring setup alert
- . Preparing devices for new site
- Manage administrate user using CMS